Sitting in Podolsk, support your Yes, but
Сидя в Подольске поддерживайте сво Да но
as a result, Belgorod residents suffer. I
в результате страдают белгородцы Я не
can’t understand what’s the point. Well, uh, I don’t understand what
фишка Ну ээ я я не понимаю что вас
confuses you, as if in this, how do I support, yes,
смущает как бы в этом как поддерживаю я
I support exactly in fact, that is,
да я поддерживаю именно по факту то есть
I, uh,
я
Hello, Good evening, I’m from the city
Здравствуйте Добрый вечер я из города
Khmelnitsky Where are you
Хмельницкий Вы
from? Khmelnitsky in the Moscow region
откуда Хмельницкий в московье
Moscow or the Moscow
Москва или московье
region Moscow region and Moscow region And more
Подмосковье а Подмосковье А
specifically the direction, well, 20 km from the Moscow Ring Road to the core of
конкретнее направление ну 20 км от МКАД
that city Tell me, I don’t [ __ ] know
коре та город Скажите я же блин не знаю
Which direction do
В какую сторону
you need the direction of Akada Well, I’m
Акада вам направление нужно Ну мне
interested Well, good I understand you, you
интересно Хорошо хорошо Я вас понял вот
know the city of the nuclear industry near Moscow
знаете
which is not Zelenograd is not nuclear Zhukovsky is
какой не Зеленоград не атомная Жуковский
not nuclear I don’t know who is nuclear
не атомна не знаю кто атомный
Podolsk Podol Podol And I knew Podolsk
Подольск подоль подоль А я знал Подольск
but didn’t know that
но не знал что там
nuclear is the main production facility there, now I’ll
атомка основной производст тепер буду
know Because I had an interlocutor from
знать Потому у меня был собеседник с
Podolsk, it’s awesome there, so photos of
Подольска там офигенно так фотографии
Podolsk I thought it was tough there, but it
Подольска думал там жесть короче а там
turns out there’s dew there  there's nothing wrong with it, it's
оказывается роса тамм Нифига себе а что
tough in the World Cup Well, somehow
там жесть в ЧМ там жесть Ну как-то
I looked at the photos of
Посмотрел фотографии
Podolsk, no matter
Подольска не
what year, the photos
смотре какого года фотографии интерес
were interesting, they were fresh Well, last year we
свеженькие были Ну мы в прошлом году
talked to
общались с
him about the prom go, maybe something has changed there in a year,
ним пром го может уже за год что-то там
but I
изменилось но я
doubt it Yes, he  especially, no, I
сомневаюсь Да он особо как бы нет я не
can’t say that it’s
могу сказать что здесь
bad here, in principle, everything is quite
плохо здесь в принципе достаточно всё
kosher
кошерно
in Belgorod, people are somehow sad.
в Белгороде людям както невесело Да
Why can’t Putin protect
почему Путин не может защитить
Belgorod? Well, I think that everything
Белгород Ну я так думаю что всё наверно
has probably gone into the wrong
зашло не в ту
phase; that’s not what we were originally counting on,
фазу не на это изначально рассчитывали
so we didn’t  that’s why they were probably preparing,
поэтому к этому не готовились поэтому
and then the same
наверно а потом таже
Belgorod, Ukraine is shelling
Бел Белгород Украина обстреливает
with impunity. Well, in general, yes, it’s a strange
безнаказанно Ну вот вообще да странная
thing, and it seems like this, and
вещь да вроде как это а
now, actually
теперь собственно
[music],
[музыка]
speaking primarily, other
говоря страдают прежде всего другие
regions of Russia are suffering. And why, for
области России которые А почему вот
example, people in Podolsk, in Moscow, in
например вот люди в Подольске в Москве в
St. Petersburg, will not come out to  there is a rally there with a
Питере не выйдут На митинг там с
demand to protect Belgorod. Well, that is,
требованием защитить Белгород Ну то есть
you don’t care about the people of Belgorod.
вам всё равно на белгородцев
Why doesn’t it happen in Belgorod
получается А почему в Белгороде не
? Well, damn, I don’t know why they don’t
выходит Ну блин я не знаю почему они не
reach Moscow; it’s a long way to go to
досту каются к Москве им Далеко ехать к
Moscow; for example, in the Moscow region
Москве вот например в Московской области
they would go to rallies in
вышли бы на митинги в
Moscow. Well  As I understand it, these
Москву Ну я так понимаю вот эти
border regions are also under martial
приграничные области там же военное
law during wars during
положение во время воен во время
martial law,
военного положения там наверное
all rallies and demonstrations in the region are probably prohibited there
запрещены все митинги демонстрации в ро
in Russia there is no martial law in
в России нет военного положения в
Ukraine there is martial law in Russia
Украине есть военного положения в России
No, well, would you, for example, here if
Нет ну а вы бы например вот у них если у
they have  prohibited, but in Moscow on Red
них запрещены вот в Москве же на Красной
Square you can hold a rally for Belgorod,
площади можно митинг сделать за Белгород
for example, Putin Protect Belgorod I just
например Путин Защити Белгород Я просто
don’t understand why all the Russians in
не понимаю почему вот все русские в
other regions just gave up on
других областях просто забили на
Belgorod. We thought that now, in short,
Белгород Мы думали что вот сейчас короче
when ours attacked Belgorod, we thought
когда бахнули наши по Белгороду думали
now all the Russians would come out to the square  and
сейчас все русские выйдут на площади и
they will say Putin Defend Belgorod and everyone stupidly doesn’t
скажут Путин Защити Белгород а всем тупо
give a damn about Belgrade Well, probably not,
получилось Ну наверное нет не в этом
that’s not the point, it’s not that someone doesn’t
дело не в том что там кому-то на что-то
give a damn about something. Although on the other
насрать Хотя с другой
hand, of course, of course, for whom you should ask someone for this,
стороны конечно за кого с кого-то за это
naturally, but with  who is who is the
надо спрашивать естественно а с кого кто
Supreme
Верховный
Commander-in-Chief? As I understand it, you need to
главнокомандующий Я так понимаю что надо
ask first
спрашивать прежде
of all from the General Staff Why did this happen? Well, the
всего с генштаба Почему так получилось
Supreme Who is who in Russia, I just don’t know; in Ukraine, the President is the Supreme Commander-in-Chief. And in Russia, who is the
главнокомандующий А в России кто
Supreme
Верховный
Commander-in-Chief, also, in my opinion,
главнокомандующий тоже по-моему
the President is also the President; Well, this is during
президент тоже президент Ну это во время
war during a war, he is always, according to the
войны во время войны он всегда он по
Constitution, the Supreme Commander-in-Chief
Конституции Верховный главнокомандующий
No, well, probably Yes, you are right, but
Нет ну наверное Да вы правы но тем не
nevertheless, the function of the Supreme
менее функция Верховного
Commander is still during a war,
командующего вс-таки во время войны да
yes. Well, as I understand it, look, who Putin
Ну я так понимаю Смотрите кто ж Путин же
signed a decree on his own and as a result,
подписал указ о сво и в результате сво
they are bombing Belgrade  that is, Putin should be
бомбят Белград то есть Путин бы должен
responsible for
нести ответственность за
this,
это
well, first of all, with What is this VKI a
ну прежде всего с Что такое это вки
special military operation not a
специальная военная операция не
war, a military operation he announced as if
война военную операцию огласил он как бы
he I don’t think he thought that he would bomb
он Я думаю не думал что будет бомбить
Belgorod, but as a result his own
Белгород но в результате его сво
Belgorod is bombed.
Белгород бомбят Мне кажется что он как
responsible for him, you need a
бы ответствен к нему нужно
question Well, you know, you could probably
вопрос Ну вы знаете можно бы наверное
present it to anyone in this case,
Кому угодно предъявить в данном случае
probably somewhere part of his guilt is understood in
наверное где-то часть его вины есть в
this Well, yes, if we
этом понят Ну так а да вот если мы
understand that part of his guilt is part of the
понимаем что часть его вины часть
General Staff and so on, why Russian Well, the Russians are
генштаба и так дальше почему русский Ну
their own  they don’t abandon it I know that yes
русские своих не бросают Я знаю такой да
And then it turns out that Belgorod is being bombed and all the
А тут получается Белгород бомбят и все
Russians have closed their eyes and are like We
русские закрыли глазки и такие вроде Мы
don’t see Belgorod in short Belgorod has been
не видим Белгород короче Белгород уже
almost gone for a year now they’ve been bombing there for a year already
почти нет его год бомбят там уже
the number of dead in total in short is over a
количество погибших суммарно короче за
hundred probably exceeded it’s just in
сотню наверное перевалило это просто в
one day 24 hit Yes, that’s it  and all the
один день 24 влупил Да вот и всем
Russians manage to give a [ __ ] from
русским получается насрать от
Birabidzhan to Leningrad and to
бирабиджана до Ленинграда да до
St. Petersburg Why don’t give a [ __ ] Why did they decide so, well,
Питера Почему насрать Почему так решили
I didn’t see, look, I didn’t see
ну я не видел смотри я не видел чтобы
people coming out somewhere Yes, demanding to
где-то выходили люди Да с требованием
protect Belg
защитить белг
Well, in this
Ну в данном
case, understand that Well, this is a
случае поймите что Ну вот эта вот
military operation Yes, how  If only it had already
военная операция Да как бы она уже
outgrown its borders, and there is
переросла свои границы свои рамки и там
already a border war going on there.
уже идёт по факту приграничная война Да
Yes, well, I can’t, for example,
там тако Да ну я не могу вот вы например
if you don’t want a rally, for example, you
ну если не хотите митинг вы например
wrote a letter to your deputy from your district demanding that it be submitted to
писали э письмо с требованием чтобы
the State Duma for consideration  There is some kind of plan for
вынести на рассмотрение Госдумы Там план
Belgorod, you
Белгорода
know, I think even if
какой-то Вы знаете я думаю даже если
they are here, that is, in the Moscow region, in
будут здесь то есть в Подмосковье в
Moscow, respectively.
Москве соответственно
That is, I think there will be no
какие-то То есть я думаю тут не будет
rallies here, in this case they
митингов в данном случае просто
will simply probably call for more roll up of
наверное будут призывать больше засучить
sleeves and, accordingly, work better in
рукава и соответственно работать лучше в
this direction.  you, like, do you
этом направлени а вы как вот вы
support yours or not, do
поддерживаете сво или нет
I support mine, well, in fact, I
поддерживаю ли я сво ну по факту я
support Yes, support is interesting, well,
поддерживаю Да поддержите интересно
look, that is, you, Alexander
хорошо вот смотри То есть вы Александр
Svyatkin, Sitting in Podolsk, support
святкин Сидя в Подольске поддерживаете
yours Yes, but as a result,
сво Да но в результате страдает
Belgorod residents suffer I can’t understand What’s the
белгородцы Я не могу понять В чём
point
фишка
Well, nothing  It confuses you, as if
Ну не по что вас смущает как бы в этом
I support this, yes, I support it in
поддерживаю я да я поддерживаю именно по
fact, that is, I help
факту то есть Я помогаю
there with my financial and other things so well.
там сво финансовое и прочее так хорошо
Yes, why do you support
Да а почему вот вы поддерживаете
financial and other things, and why don’t you
финансовое и прочее а почему вы не
support the organizational defense of
поддержите организационно защиту
Belgorod, for example, take come to That’s
Белгорода например взять прийти к Вот
who you have  State Duma deputy from your
кто у вас депутат Госдумы от вашего
district from your district there
округа от вашего там
Well, there’s probably unlikely
района Ну от района наверное вряд ли
to be a deputy from the district And who directly from the
будет депутат А кто непосредственно э от
district Podolsk city district
округа округ Подольский городской округ
is a deputy in the State Duma I honestly
есть ели депутат в госдуме Я честно
doubt it, in fact, that’s probably where it’s after all Uh-huh It
сомневаюсь на самом деле
seems to me that it’s necessary Well  in any
Угу Мне кажется что нужно Ну в любом
case, you have headquarters there, the LDPR, the headquarters of
случае у вас есть штабы там ЛДПР штабы
United Russia, the headquarters of a fair Russia,
Единой России штабы справедливой России
well, that is, they would organize
ну то есть Взяли бы организовали ещё
three more of these who support their own, like you,
трёх таких поддерживающих сво Как вы да
and they would go and go to all the headquarters and
и пошли бы прошлись по всем штабам и
say, look, well, this is not the order,
сказали смотрите Ну это не порядок с нас
the Ukrainians stupidly laugh at us, in short, yes  that they are
украинцы тупо ржут короче да что они
killing Belgorod residents, yes, Russia is a great
убивают белгородцев да Россия великая
power that cannot protect Belgorod, you
держава не может защитить Белгород вы
are sitting in this State Duma, and you
сидите протирает в этой госдуме Да и не
can’t protect Belgrade, let’s
можете защитить Белград давайте что-то
do something, well, you can do this or not.
делайте ну можете такое сделать или нет
Why do you think that Belgorod is not
А почему вы думаете что Белгород не
protecting Belgorod is protecting from Well, it doesn’t
защищает Белгород защищает от Ну не
protect because  that they’ve been dying there for a year
защищает потому что там умирают год
already, and on New Year’s Eve, damn 24
умирает уже а под Новый год блин 24
died. Well, if you hit the
умерло Ну если ударить кассетным
center of the city with cluster munitions, it
боеприпасами по центру города прави
means they’re not defending. Because if they were
значит не защищают Потому что если бы
defending, they would have taken the troops not from Avdiivka, they would have
защищали взяли б войска не авдеевку
played, they would have pushed the troops in the
игрались бы отодвинули войска на
Kharkov direction away from Belgorod and that’s it.
Харьковском направлении от Белгорода и
Well, you understand it yourself  this act of
Ну Понимаете вот сам вот этот акт что
hitting the city center with candy
бьют по центру города конфетные
ammunition shows on the other hand
боеприпасами показывает с другой стороны
that this word was really
что вот это слово действительно была
needed No, it’s clear that Ukraine is a
нужна Нет так это понятно то что Украина
terrorist there, the Nazis, the
террорист там нацисты это всё это все
whole world has already seen all this Yes, but yes it turns out,
уже весь мир увидел Да но да получается
look that Putin is there and, for example,
смотрите что Путин там и например
Medvedev  they cried like America France
Медведев поплакали типа Америке Франции
and Germany that Ukraine is hitting Belgorod yes
и Германии что Украина бьёт по белгру да
And they answered that Ukraine has
А те взяли ответили что Украина имеет
the right to defend itself because Russia is the
право защищаться потому что Россия
aggressor they crap everything like Putin
агрессор всё обосрали типа Путина
Medvedev and said go to hell, in short, they
Медведева и сказали Идите нахрен короче
will continue to bomb your Belgorod, that
будут бомбить дальше ваш Белгород то
is, Belgorod does not make it any easier, look
есть Белгород от этого не легче смотрите
before the beginning  no one bombed their own Belgorod.
до начала сво Белгород никто не бомбил
Here they are now, I meet people from
Вот они сейчас я встречаю людей из
Belgorod, I say, look, no one
Белгорода говорю смотрите вас никто не
bombed you, they say No, but now they are
бомбил они говорят Не бомбил а сейчас
bombing, they are bombing, I say, who is
бомбят говорят бомбят Я говорю а кто
to blame, they say,
виноват они говорят
Putin and all sorts of morons from Podolsk who
Путин и всякие [__] из Подольска кото
will support nya
поддержит ня
sri Belgorod was bombed Donbass yes yes  Well,
сри Белгород набомбили Донбасс да да Ну
look Donbass Yes, Donbass it turns out
смотри Донбасс Да Донбасс это получается
Putin has undertaken to defend Donbass Yes, but he
Путин взялся защищать Донбасс Да а не
can’t defend Belgorod, then he can damn well
может защитить Белгород то может блин
say Listen, I can’t
взять и сказать Слушай я не могу
defend now they are shelling both Donbass and
защитить сейчас обстреливают и Донбасс и
Belgorod Yes, maybe he can still go ahead and
Белгород Да может всё-таки взять и
say Damn, let’s withdraw troops from
сказать Блин давайте вывожу войска с
Donbass from Crimea  and that’s it, and the
Донбасса с Крыма и всё и перестают на
next day they stop shelling both Donbass and
следующий день обстрелять и Донбасс и
Belgrade Well, it’s just that Putin, if
Белград Ну это ж просто если Путин если
Putin can’t protect Well, he had his own
Путин не может защитить Ну он сво
idea that he would protect Donbass now
задумал что он сечас и защитит Донбасс
Donbass won’t shell in Donetsk
Донбасс не будет обстреливать в Донецке
everything in Donetsk people said they
все в Донецке люди говорили они
met Russian troops they said everything
встречали российские войска говорили всё
Now they won’t fire at you, but now they’re
сейчас не будут обстреливать а теперь
sitting there, [ __ ] crazy, they’ve been shooting for 2 years, they’re still
сидят охуевшие 2 года бля стреляют ещё
shooting at themselves like crazy, they’re shooting at themselves more than
как как не в себя больше стреляют чем
before, they used to fly in once every six months, and
раньше раньше прилетало раз в полгода А
now they’re stupidly attacking Donetsk every day,
теперь тупо каждый день наваливает на
and Belgrade is generally freaking out and
Донецк а Белград вообще офигевший
says, damn, they didn’t shoot
говорит бля вобще не стреляли
me at all with the Belgorod soundboard.  eyes
вообще меня декой Белгорода У вас глаза
reddened, pressure, he says, you understand, he
покраснели давление он говорит понимаете
says that we weren’t bombed at all, we didn’t
говорит что нас не бомбили вообще мы не
know what it
знали что это
was to us that Donbass, people from Belgorod say,
такое нам тот Донбасс говорят люди из
you understand, yes, what are
понимаете да Что вы говорите к кого
you talking to whom? Which people from Belgorod are you serving? Look, I’ll
Каких людей из бел вы слу Смотри я вот
say this. You’re a coward, you know why, so come on, come
что скажу Ты трус знаешь почему пому
on  let's go badly, let's go badly, I'm
давай давай безладно давай безладно
undercut You're a coward, you'll never
давай я подрез Ты трус ты никогда не
come to your deputies so they
выйдешь к своим депутатам чтобы они
can defend the white never everything come on
защитили бел никогда всё давай
lust come on because the Russians don't abandon their own
похоть давай потому что русские своих не
Yes He'll never get away from the
бросают Да Никогда он не выйдет он от
word in short Contact the deputy
слова короче Обратитесь к депутату у
his damn ass is shrinking Yes put it
него же блин очко сжимается Да поставьте
plus, you saw it when like
плюс Вы же это видели когда типа А
Why Take Gather, go through the
почему Возьмите Соберите пройдитесь по
parties in short, when he is such a [ __ ], how is
партиям короче по при он такой [__] как
he from the idea that he should
это он от представления что он должен
go to the party office to ask a deputy to
зайти в офис партии спросить депутата
say something, this badge is scary, yes, a
что-то сказать это бляха это страшно да
rally is actually from the word rally  them
митинг это вообще от слова митинг у них
there verbal in short like an
там вербальный короче типа начинается
earthquake begins writing on th Telegram directly at
землетрясение пись на й Telegram прям
once axis VN
зараз ось ВН
apok tse more and more
апок це дуже и дуже
politely
важливо